Well, I'm very relieved.
정말 안심이에요
I've got that behind me.
그건 다 지난 일이에요
No more human testing for me.
인체 실험은 이제 안 해요
We'll have one final look at my abysmal results and move swiftly on.
최악의 결과를 마지막으로 보고 다음으로 넘어가죠
The time has come for us to be working with the frontier.
우리가 개척지와 함께 일할 때가 왔어요
And we're going to start with GPT four mini, the miniature version.
GPT 4 미니부터 시작할 거예요 미니 버전이죠
Um, but it's not so many.
그렇게 많지는 않아요
It's still a mighty frontier.
여전히 거대한 개척지죠
LLM.
`LM'요
Um, and it's going to be exciting to see how it fares compared to the other models we've worked with.
우리가 함께 작업한 다른 모델과 비교해서 얼마나 잘 팔릴지 궁금해요
So first of all, we need to work on our prompt for GPT four.
먼저 GPT 4 프롬프트를 작업해야 하는데요
And um, this is I mean, this is an extremely important part of your learning because this is where
이건 여러분이 배우는 데 있어 아주 중요한 부분이에요 개척자 모델을
we see how we will solve real commercial problems like this using a frontier model.
통해 이런 상업적 문제를 어떻게 해결할지 볼 수 있으니까요
But a lot of this should again be pretty much second nature to you, because it's so similar to many
하지만 많은 부분이 여러분에게 제2의 본성이 되어야 합니다 왜냐하면 이전에 했던 많은 작업들과
of the tasks we've done before.
비슷하기 때문이죠
The first thing we're going to do is write a function messages for item.
가장 먼저 항목에 대한 함수 메시지를 작성할게요
Given our data point, we're going to want to turn that into a prompt for GPT four, which comes in
데이터 포인트에 따라 GPT 4를 위한 프롬프트로 바꾸겠습니다 이
the form of one of these messages lists, which you remember is a list of dictionaries.
메시지 목록 중 하나의 형태로 온 거죠 여러분이 기억하시는 사전 목록이요
So this is how we build up that list of dictionaries.
이렇게 사전 목록을 만드는 거예요
It starts with a system message, which is going to be in our case you estimate prices of items, reply
시스템 메시지로 시작합니다 이 경우엔 물품의 가격을 추정하고 가격으로만
only with the price, no explanation.
답장합니다 설명 없이요
And then for the user prompt, we are going to take the test prompt from this item, which you've seen
사용자 프롬프트는 이 아이템에서 테스트 프롬프트를 가져옵니다 많이 보셨던
many times.
거죠
But we are going to do a little bit of data munging to it.
데이터 비트를 좀 뒤져볼게요
So first of all, I'm going to strip out this text to the nearest dollar.
먼저 이 텍스트를 $로 줄여볼게요
The reason I'm doing that well actually the reason I should say the reason I put that in in the first
제가 그렇게 하는 이유는 아니, 그렇게 말해야 하는 이유는 이걸
place is that later when we work with open source models, um, we'll be we'll be wanting to give those
처음에 넣은 이유는 나중에 오픈 소스 모델로 작업할 때 오픈 소스 모델을 제공해
open source models, make the problem as easy as it possibly can be, because they've got a lot to learn
최대한 쉽게 문제를 해결하게 될 테니까요 배울 게 많은데 그걸 할
and they've only got the humble 8 billion parameters to do it in.
80억 매개 변수밖에 없으니까요
When it comes to these frontier models, they are obviously much more capable, much more powerful,
개척 시대의 모델은 훨씬 더 강력하고 능력이 뛰어나며 똑같은
and they don't need the same kind of guardrails.
가드레일도 필요 없죠
GPT four or mini is going to be very happy, uh, predicting prices, including cents, and it knows
GPT4나 미니가 아주 좋아할 거예요 센트를 포함해서 가격을 예측할 수 있으니까요 어떤 게 효과가 있는지
exactly what it's working with.
정확히 알고 있죠
So this was an unnecessary guardrail in this case.
이 경우에는 불필요한 가드레일이었어요
So I took it out.
그래서 뺐어요
I also take out the very end of the prompt, which is where it says price is dollars.
프롬프트 맨 끝도 제거했어요 가격은 달러라는 곳이죠
The reason I take that out is you will see when it comes to building this list of messages, I first
이걸 제거한 이유는 메시지 목록을 만들 때 시스템 역할에
put in the system prompt under the system role.
먼저 입력하기 때문이에요.
I then add user and I put in the user prompt, and then I put in one more message which comes from assistant.
사용자를 추가하고 사용자 프롬프트를 입력합니다 그리고 보조에서 오는 메시지를 하나 더 입력해요
In other words, it's like it's the reply from GPT four mini.
GPT4 미니의 회신 같은 거죠
Uh.
네
And that reply is price is dollars and then nothing.
가격은 달러라는 대답만 남죠
Uh, and that makes it unbearably desperate to fill in that next token with the price, because this
그래서 참을 수 없을 정도로 다음 토큰에 가격을 적고 싶어지죠 이게
is apparently the response coming back from the assistant from it.
조수로부터 돌아오는 응답이니까요
Uh, and so you've really we've, we've we've teed it up so that it feels, uh, like it absolutely
그래서 저희는 그 부분을 가장 그럴듯한 다음 토큰으로 채워야
has to fill that in with the most plausible next token, which is the most likely price of this product.
한다고 생각했어요 이 제품을 살 때 가장 그럴듯한 가격으로요
So that that trick of sort of having it be the assistant's response and filling it in that way is,
그래서 조수처럼 반응하게 해서 그렇게 채우는 게 실험해보기에
uh, is a good one to experiment with.
좋은 방법이죠
Um, so that's what we do.
그게 우리 일이에요
Let's just quickly, uh, try this out and have a look at this.
빨리 이걸 시험해 보고 살펴보죠
So, so if we say, like, messages for and put in the first test data point just to see what this looks
메시지 for get을 입력하고 첫 번째 테스트 데이터 포인트를 입력하면
like, what we get is, uh, roll system and then this is the system prompt.
롤 시스템과 시스템 프롬프트가 뜨죠
Hopefully that makes total sense.
이해가 되면 좋겠네요
Then roll user and the content is how much does this cost.
롤 유저를 선택하고 콘텐츠는 비용이죠
And then an item and, uh, yeah, I'm guessing, uh, some kind of, uh, horrible memory of having
그리고 제 생각에 이 물건들은 끔찍한 메모리일 것 같아요 이 물건들의 가격을
to go through and guess the prices of all of these things.
전부 다 맞춰야 했으니까요
Just looking at it fills me with dread.
보기만 해도 겁이 나요
Uh, but it won't be my problem this time.
이번엔 제 문제가 아니에요
It's going to be GPT four or Mini's problem.
GPT 4와 미니 중 선택해야 해요
So it gets given that as part of the user prompt, and then it's given the assistance response.
사용자 프롬프트의 일부로 그걸 받게 되죠 그런 다음 지원 응답을 받게 돼요
It's own response price is dollars.
그 자체로 보상가는 달러예요
And then it will try and continue this conversation.
그럼 이 대화를 계속하려고 할 거예요
Um, so this is a great, uh, prompt for us to be sending GPT four.
GPT 4를 보내기에 좋은 타이밍인 셈이죠
Oh, then next, just one more little quick function, a utility called Get Price that I've written
다음, 짧은 함수가 하나 더 있어요 여기 쓴 Get Price라는
here, which takes a string s, uh, and, uh, extracts from that string a floating point number within
유틸리티로 문자열 s를 이용해 그 문자열에서 부동점 수를 추출해요
Um, so that if, for example, we get a string back from GPT four, like, like, um, the price is
예를 들어 GPT 4에서 문자열을 받으면 가격이 대략 1달러 99센트예요
Um, because blah blah.
99살요
If it doesn't obey my instructions and it decides to just be talkative about it, we will still strip
제 지시를 따르지 않고 계속 떠들면 그래도 옷을 벗을 거예요
out.
이런, 미안해요
Oops.
밝히지 마세요
We will still strip out the 99.99 there.
99는 여전히 제거할 거예요 99달러 나왔어요
So it will.
그럴 거예요
It will work.
잘될 거예요
Uh, okay.
네
That brings us I will carefully scroll down.
이제 조심스럽게 스크롤을 내릴게요
That brings us to the big, uh, function.
이제 큰 함수로 넘어가죠
This is.
맞아요
This is the real deal.
이건 진짜예요
Uh, we are going to call GPT four mini with an item, and this is how we're going to do it.
GPT 4 미니를 항목과 함께 호출할 겁니다 이렇게 하는 거죠
Of course, we say OpenAI ChatGPT completions dot create.
OpenAI 챗GPT완료 .Create라고 하죠
Uh, we pass in a model, uh, GPT four mini.
GPT 4 미니 모델을 통과했어요
Uh, we, uh, pass in the messages for that item, which we use the function that we just talked about,
그 아이템에 대한 메시지를 전달합니다 방금 말씀드린 함수를 사용해서요
this seed is a way to tell GPT four that we want to try and have this be reproducible, so that it gives
이 시드는 GPT 4에 이걸 재생하고 싶다고 말하는 방법입니다 같은 입력으로
the same answer with the same inputs.
같은 답을 주도록요
Now, our GPT, OpenAI can't always honour this because they make changes to their model.
오픈아이는 기존 GPT 모델을 변경하기 때문에 늘 이 방식을 고수할 순 없죠
And so sometimes the model will change.
그래서 모델이 바뀌기도 해요
And so so this number will change.
이 숫자는 바뀔 거예요
But it does its best, all else being equal.
하지만 모든 게 평등하니 최선을 다하죠
Then if you call this twice with the same seed you should get the same answer.
그럼 같은 씨앗으로 두 번 부르면 같은 답이 나오겠네요? Get it
So that's good to know.
좋은 정보네요
And then max tokens I keep that number small because you know we've given it such a great tee up, we
최대 토큰은 작게 두겠습니다 티업이 훌륭하기 때문이죠 가격이
can expect it really will fill in the price as indeed it does.
채워질 거라고 기대할 수 있어요
And so we don't need to waste our money, uh, bringing back more tokens than that.
그러니 더 많은 토큰을 가져오느라 돈을 낭비할 필요가 없죠
And I should say, because we do this, uh, this whole operation is very, very cheap across all 250
이런 작업을 하기 때문에 250개의 데이터 포인트에 걸쳐 이 전체 작업은 아주
data points.
저렴해요
Um, it's still for me in the US anyway.
미국에 있는 제 자리예요
Costs way less than a than a, um.
가격은 그보다도 훨씬 less예요
Well, less that's that's an ascent less than so little that it won't show up in the user interface.
음, less 아, 그러니까 등급이 너무 적어서 사용자 인터페이스에서 안 보이는 거죠
It's less than a fraction of a cent.
1센트도 안 되는 less요
So it's very cheap indeed to use because it's a short input tokens and a and a five output tokens.
아주 저렴합니다 짧은 입력 토큰과 5개의 출력 토큰을 사용하니까요
And just before I want to be careful not to reveal what goes on.
그리고 조심하기 전에 무슨 일이 일어나는지 말해야죠
Uh, uh, just before let's just quickly try this out.
그 전에 이걸 빨리 해 보죠
Let's run GPT four.
GPT 4를 돌려 보죠
Oh, mini, and let's call it with Test of Zero to see how it performs.
테스트 오브 제로로 성능을 확인해 보죠
Uh, we run that and it gets back the answer 260.0.
그걸 실행하면 답이 260으로 나와요 0살요
Uh, so you can see it went through it called GPT four mini.
GPT 4 미니라는 걸 거쳤네요
It then got back, it sent in something.
그리고 뭔가 보내왔죠
It sent in exactly this uh, and then with what it got back, it put it through this function and stripped
이것과 똑같은 것을 보냈고 받은 정보를 바탕으로 이 함수를 적용해서 260개를
out 260 as the price for the first item.
제거해 첫 번째 물건의 가격을 맞췄어요.
Uh, we might as well find out what is the price of the first item?
일단 첫 번째 물건의 가격부터 알아보죠
Some, uh.
조금요
So it gets to 60 and the number is three, seven, four.
60까지 가면 숫자는 3, 7, 4가 되죠
So it was quite far out with that one.
그래서 좀 멀리 갔죠
Um.
네
All right, well, the time has come to call tester dot test passing in GPT for a mini and test.
이제 테스터와 GPT 테스트를 통과할 시간입니다 미니 테스트죠
And you've seen a few times now that I have already run this because it comes pretty fast, but it still
제가 이미 실행해본 걸 몇 번 보셨을 겁니다 꽤 빠르거든요 하지만 전체를 다 하려면
takes maybe 2 or 3 minutes to do the whole lot.
2, 3분 정도 걸려요
So I didn't want you to have to sit there while it was happening and so I can scroll through the outcome.
여러분이 거기 앉아 계시는 동안 결과를 스크롤할 수 있게 하고 싶진 않았어요
But before I do so, uh, have your guess about how GPT four mini will perform.
하지만 그 전에 GPT 4 미니가 어떻게 달릴지 한번 맞혀 보세요
How will it fare against, uh, original?
오리지널과 비교하면 어떨까요?
Against the average number?
평균 수보다요?
How will it fare against humanity as represented by by yours truly?
제가 대표하는 인류에 대한 반발은 어떨까요?
And how will it fare against the most advanced traditional models, which had the benefit of 400,000
또한 훈련용 400,000대의 모델이 있는 최첨단 전통 모델과는 어떻게
examples to train on?
경쟁할까요?
Let's see.
어디 보죠
So I executed this and this is what I got.
그래서 이걸 실행했더니 이렇게 됐어요
So some yellows and reds we see indeed the reproducibility you can see was I it gave identical guess
노란색과 빨간색은 재생률이 아주 높아요 아까와
of 260 um against the the truth there.
같은 260개를 예상했죠
Um so you can see some greens and some reds.
녹색과 붉은색이 보이죠
Lots of greens, lots of greens but still yellows and reds as well.
녹색은 많지만 노란색과 빨간색도 있어요
Uh, I'm going to speed up.
속도를 높일게요
Wow, a big bunch of greens there.
채소가 정말 많네요
Some more reds, some more greens.
붉은색과 녹색도 더 넣고요
And here is the answer I give you the GPT four mini frontier model results.
답은 이겁니다 GPT 4 미니 프론티어 모델 결과죠
It has crushed the others.
다른 건 다 박살 났죠
Crushed them.
박살을 냈죠
You can see that, uh, it has come in at $79.58.
여기 보시면 79달러가 들어 있어요 58살요
Uh, definitely doing better than humanity, doing better than the, um, the other, uh, um, all
확실히 인간보다 낫고 다른 모든 모델보다 나아요 무작위 숲도 포함해서요
of the other models, including, uh, random forest by far, and without having any training data at
훈련 데이터도 전혀 없이 순수하게 설명만 듣고
all Based purely on getting the description and continuing that token sequence.
토큰 시퀀스를 계속하는 거죠
And as I say, whereas there is some risk of test of training data contamination, I think it's unlikely
훈련용 데이터 오염을 테스트할 위험은 있지만 그럴 가능성은 희박합니다
because there are almost no cases of it getting it exactly right.
정확히 해낼 경우가 거의 없으니까요
So it's not as if it was regurgitating something it already knew.
이미 알고 있던 걸 토해낸 게 아니에요
Um, it's just got such a significant, uh, worldly knowledge that it's been trained on that.
세속적인 지식이 아주 풍부해서 그런 쪽으로 훈련된 거죠
It has a great viewpoint as to how much a tire costs, how much a headlamp costs, how much a shower
타이어 가격, 전조등 가격 샤워 수도꼭지 등 다른 비용을 알려주는 좋은
faucet costs, and all the other things.
관점이 있어요
That gave me tremendous problem because I have no clue.
그게 큰 문제였어요 전혀 알 수가 없었거든요
Uh, but it had a very good clue indeed.
하지만 아주 좋은 단서가 있었죠
Um, and so much of a clue that it beat all of the models that had worked on this.
이 작업에 참여한 모든 모델보다 낫다는 걸 알 수 있었죠
So that's pretty cool.
정말 멋져요
I did enjoy seeing this a lot.
이 장면을 보는 게 즐거웠어요
And, uh, in the next video, we will take it up a notch and see how it's it's bigger cousin fares.
다음 영상에서는 수준을 한 단계 높여서 더 큰 사촌이 어떻게 하는지 보죠